我的新书《隐藏的真相》讨论了一个很大的问题
My new book The Hidden Reality takes on a grand question:
我们的宇宙是唯一的吗
Is our universe the only universe?
越来越多像我这样的科学家相信
You see, there's a growing belief among scientists like me
我们也许只是茫茫空间里众多宇宙中的
that ours may only be one among many universes
其中一个
populating a gigantic cosmos.
在《隐藏的真相》中  我在不涉及
In The Hidden Reality, I explore this possibility
任何数学和物理知识的情况下
without presuming any knowledge of mathematics or physics
向读者阐释了这一可能
on the part of the reader.
可笑至极
Hysterical.
很高兴你说服我来这里
I'm glad you talked me into this.
咱们平时太辛苦了  有时候偷个闲
We work so hard, sometimes, it's nice to goof off
-干点儿蠢事儿也挺好的  -没错
- and do something silly. - Agreed.
你等着听他跟大家胡扯沃纳·海森堡吧
Wait till you hear how he dumbs down Werner Heisenberg for the crowd.
你都会觉得自己是在德云社听相声
You may actually believe you're in a comedy club.
你可以觉得海森堡的"不确定性原理"
You can think about Heisenberg's "uncertainty principle"
就像是在某些中国餐馆里的
much like the special order menu
每日特供菜单  你会发现有些菜
that you find in certain Chinese restaurants, where you have
在A栏里  有些菜在B栏里
dishes in column A and other dishes in column B,
如果你点了A栏里的第一道菜
and if you order the first dish in column A,
你就不能点B栏里的第一道菜了
you can't order the corresponding dish in column B.
这就有点像"不确定性原理"
That's sort of like the "uncertainly principle."
当里个当
Ba-dum-bump.
说起来  我听说了霍华德和
Say, I heard an interesting tidbit
伯纳黛特的一件趣事儿
about Howard and Bernadette.
你开玩笑吧  艾米  跟我聊八卦
Really, Amy? Gossip?
我对你失望了
I'm disappointed in you.
别急啊
No, now.
进化生物学家罗宾·邓巴把八卦定义为
Evolutionary biologist Robin Dunbar has identified gossip
一种有助于在大群体内维系感情的手段
as an aid to social bonding in large groups.
恕我直言  全是扯淡
Forgive my language, but "poppycock".
万一不是呢
What if he's right?
如果没有八卦
And by not participating in gossip,
社会就会分裂成为
society breaks down into
一个个纹身摩托车手组成的野蛮小帮派
small feral bands of tattooed motorcycle riders
为了最后几罐金枪鱼罐头打得死去活来
fighting to the death over the last few cans of tuna fish.
好吧
Fine.
用城市音乐[黑人音乐]的术语来说
In the parlance of the urban music scene,
"你想跟我说啥"
"what's the 4-1-1"?
伯纳黛特想和霍华德分手
Bernadette is thinking about breaking up with Howard.
我觉得咱国家的金枪鱼罐头还是安全的
I believe our nation's tuna cans are safe.
抱歉等下聊  格林博士  我能提问吗
Excuse me. Dr. Greene, question?
请讲
Yes?
您一直致力于
You've dedicated your life's work
向公众宣传灌输一些
to educating the general populace
复杂的科学理念
about complex scientific ideas.
对  差不多
Yes, in part.
您有没有考虑过
Have you ever considered
干点儿更有意义的事儿呢
trying to do something useful?
比如  给老人念书
Perhaps, reading to the elderly?
你说什么
Excuse me?
嗯  不过别念你的书  念点儿他们喜欢的
Yeah, but not your books; something they might enjoy.
当然咯  我开玩笑啦  支持你哦
I kid, of course. Big fan.
生活大爆炸
第四季第二十集
-射得好  -多谢
- Nice shot. - Thank you.
我父亲从小就在训练我射箭了
My father taught me archery as a child.
真没想到这项运动居然能唤起
It's odd how the activity
印象中凯马特波旁酒的醇香[他父亲酗酒]
brings back the smell of Kmart bourbon.
-漂亮  -我知道
- Perfect. - I know.
我肯定能当个出色的精灵
What an elf I would have made.
你觉得你在干嘛呢
What do you think you're doing?
冲着靶子射箭啊
Shooting at a target?
拿什么射
With what?
-箭啊  -你开玩笑吧
- An arrow. - Really?
我都没看见你从箭筒里取箭
I didn't see you draw one from your quiver.
我不会这么傻的  谢尔顿
I'm not going to do that, Sheldon.
莱纳德  任天堂的人在重现真实的
Leonard, the people at Nintendo can only go so far
竞技体验这方面只能做到这份儿上了
in helping us recreate an actual athletic experience.
剩下的得靠我们自己
We have to do our part, too.
虽然比较出乎意料  但是
That was uncalled for, but...
我还是配合一下吧  痛
I'll play along. Ow.
我昨晚和艾米有一次非凡的体验
I had an unusual experience with Amy last night.
真的吗  你怎么感觉出来的
Really? How could you tell?
她想和我聊八卦
She was attempting to engage me in gossip.
-你肯定不干  -对
- Mm. You don't say. - Yes.
我觉得跟佩妮混时间长了
I think prolonged exposure to Penny
她也变得有点儿女孩子气了
has turned her into a bit of a Gabby Gertie.
什么八卦啊
So, what's the gossip?
拜托  我都说了
Oh, please, I was just pointing it out.
我对这种东西完全没兴趣
I have no desire to engage in the activity.
好吧  那就别跟我说了
Fine, don't tell me.
好吧  听着
All right, get this.
伯纳黛特想和霍华德分手
Bernadette is thinking about breaking up with Howard.
真糟糕  出什么事儿了啊
That's too bad. I wonder what happened.
不好说  我只能推测一下
Mm, it's hard to say. I can only speculate
根据我观察我父母的婚姻分崩离析
based on the data I collected
所得到的数据
watching my parents' marriage implode.
在我们家  我妈一头扎进了宗教的海洋
In that case, the woman dives into religion,
而我爸则一头扎进了金发女酒保的怀抱
while the man dives into a bottle-blonde bartender
那女人还想用超级英雄的玩具收买我呢
who tries to buy my love with action figures.
啊哦  没箭了
Oop! Out of arrows.
天啊  你这游戏买的真是太值了
Boy, you sure get your money's worth out of these games.
-普丽娅  我能进来吗  -进吧
- Priya, can I come in? - Sure.
天啊
Oh, God.
-怎么了  -没事
- What? - It's okay.
你不知道罢了  我来处理吧
You didn't know. I'll take care of it.
我  我做错什么了
What-what did I do?
谢尔顿禁止在离镜子
Sheldon doesn't allow flossing
这么近的地方用牙线
that close to the mirror.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
会溅上去的
It's a splatter thing.
地板上贴了一小段胶带
There's a little piece of tape on the floor
你得站在胶带后面
you're supposed to stand behind.
-太雷人了  -我知道
- That's madness. - I know.
照做吧  待会儿会有大检查
Just do it. There's a big inspection coming up,
我可不想失去看电视的特权
and I don't want to lose my TV privileges.
你迟早得让我看一眼
You really need to let me take a look
那个室友协议
at that roommate agreement, one of these days.
有这必要吗
Mm, I don't know.
我俩各自请律师对簿公堂吗
I get a lawyer, he gets a lawyer...
还是老老实实站黄线后算了
It's just easier to stand behind the tape.
对了  我一个同事说
Oh, by the way, a fellow at work said
要给我周末道奇队比赛的门票
I could use his Dodger tickets this weekend.
-应该很好玩吧  -那是
- Does that sound like fun?  - Yeah!
道奇是棒球队  对吧
Dodgers are baseball, right?
你到时候得给我解释一下比赛规则
You'll need to explain the game to me.
规则很复杂的
Mm, it's complicated.
不过在我看来  棒球的精髓就是
But as I remember it, the essentials are
最后才被选中  被球打  痛哭  回家
"get chosen last, get hit by the ball, cry, go home" .
不管怎么说都好  我有四张票呢
Well, regardless, I've got four tickets.
叫上伯纳黛特和霍华德一起去好吗
And I was thinking we can bring Bernadette and Howard.
伯纳黛特真的很有意思
She's really interesting,
我想我早晚也能适应霍华德的存在
and I bet I can get used to him.
叫他俩去可能
Well, it might not be a great idea
-不太好  -为什么
- to invite those two.  - Why not?
别跟别人说是我说的
Don't tell anybody I told you,
不过据说伯纳黛特可能要跟霍华德分手
but I heard she might be breaking up with him.
太可惜了
Oh...too bad...
不过我倒认识一个会因此高兴的人
Although I do know one person for whom that's good news.
真的吗  谁呀
Really? Who?
我哥
My brother.
他超喜欢伯纳黛特
He's got a big crush on Bernadette.
什么
What?
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
没有  我看到过他给她写的诗
No. I found poems he wrote about her.
超诡异的
Very disturbing.
"噢  伯纳黛特  吹响我的单簧管吧"
"Oh, Bernadette, please play my clarinet" .
-这太难以置信了  -就是说呀
- Wow, that's hard to believe.  - Yes.
这么多年来  我家所有人
And for years, everyone in my family
都坚信他有同性恋倾向呢
was convinced that he was the clarinet enthusiast.
这条黄线又是干嘛的
What's that piece of tape?
你用不着担心这个  反正你坐着上厕所
Oh, that one doesn't apply to you. You sit.
近来好吗
How's it going?
还不错  你听说伯纳黛特和霍华德的事了吗
Not too bad. Did you hear about Howard and Bernadette?
当然了  你是怎么知道的
'Course I heard about it. How did you hear about it?
我是听谢尔顿说的
I heard about it from Sheldon.
-他是听艾米说的  -该死
- He got it from Amy.  - Oh, damn it.
我还叫艾米绝对不能告诉别人呢
I told Amy that in the strictest confidence.
有些人还真是大嘴巴
Boy, some people are such blabbermouths.
随便啦
Well, whatever.
我相信伯纳黛特肯定能找到更好的
I'm sure Bernadette can do better.
你觉得一个有选择性缄默症  酗酒问题
Do you think a sexually ambivalent Indian astrophysicist
而且性取向不稳定的印度天体物理学家
with selective mutism and alcohol issues is better than
比体重一百磅  跟老妈住的犹太人强吗
a hundred-pound Jewish guy who lives with his mom?
你开玩笑吧  拉杰喜欢伯纳黛特吗
You are kidding. Raj likes Bernadette?
我可没说是拉杰  谁说是拉杰了
I didn't say Raj. Who said Raj?
好了  快说
Okay, give.
你怎么知道的  他自己说的吗
How do you know? Did he tell you?
-不是  -那是谁说的
- No.  - Well, then who?
我不能说
I can't say...
普丽娅告诉你的  真是个小八婆
Priya told you. What a little gossip.
一个女人这么八婆可不好  莱纳德
You know, not an attractive quality in a woman, Leonard.
我不是说她坏话  只是个人看法而已
Not judging, just my opinion.
问题是  要是这件事传开了
Well, The point is, if this got out,
可能会影响霍华德和拉杰的友谊
it would destroy Howard and Raj's friendship.
你用不着担心
You don't have to worry.
我又不像艾米和普丽娅  我嘴可严呢
Unlike Amy and Priya, I know how to keep a secret.
这件事一开始就是你告诉艾米的
You're the one who told Amy in the first place.
我有叫她保密呀
In confidence.
你好  妈妈  你好  爸爸  你们好吗
Hello, Mummy. Hello, Daddy. How are you?
我们是穷国里的富人
We're very rich in a very poor country.
所以  总的来说  没啥好抱怨的
So, all in all, can't complain.
普丽娅
So, Priya,
你在你哥家住的还好吗
how are enjoying staying with your brother?
还不错  但是如果我要继续
It's fine. But if I'm going to stay
留在洛杉矶的话
in Los Angeles much longer,
我想我应该找个地方自己搬出去住
I think I should get my own place.
为什么
Why?
拉杰没给你提供舒适的环境吗
Is Rajesh not making you feel comfortable?
拉杰  你为什么不给你妹妹提供舒适的环境
Rajesh, why aren't you making your sister comfortable?
我有啊
I am making her comfortable.
再说  反正她一半时间
Besides, she's not sleeping here
都不在我这睡
half the time anyw...
什么
What?
那你去哪睡  普丽娅
Where are you sleeping, Priya?
这只是修辞说法而已  爸
It's a figure of speech, Daddy.
意思是说我工作到很晚
It means I-I work late.
别说你交了个美国男朋友
Please tell me you're not dating an American.
我就知道会这样
I knew this would happen.
拉杰  你是不是让你妹
Rajesh, are you letting your sister
跟那个叫霍华德的小子交往了
date that little Howard boy?
等会  如果她真交了个美国男朋友的话
Now, hold on. If she is dating an American,
找霍华德也不错呀
that's not a bad way to go.
他是犹太人
He's Jewish.
犹太人都很成功的
Those chaps are very successful,
而且他们不怎么喝酒
and they don't drink a lot.
这都不重要啦  霍华德有女朋友的
It-It doesn't matter. Howard has a girlfriend.
-那只是目前而已  -这是什么意思
- For now.  - What does that mean?
晚点再告诉你
I'll tell you later.
他跟伯纳黛特之间出问题了吗
Is something going on with him and Bernadette?
-伯纳黛特是谁  -听起来不像是犹太人
- Who's Bernadette?  - Doesn't sound Jewish.
听名字哪听得出来
You can't tell by that.
威诺纳·赖德[美国女演员]也是犹太人啊
Winona Ryder is Jewish.
好吧  这个话题先放一放
Okay, we're getting off the subject.
拉杰  你要更努力地
Rajesh, I want you to try harder
让你妹妹觉得宾至如归
to make your sister feel welcome.
谢谢爸爸
Thank you, Daddy.
别担心  只要是我的东西  我都会跟她分享的
Don't worry. Everything I have, I share with her.
包括我朋友莱...
Including my friend Leon...
晚安妈妈  晚安爸爸
Good night, Mummy. Good night, Daddy.
天啊  我脚趾都被你踩断了
Oh, my God, I think you broke my toe!
谁叫你多嘴的
You should have kept your mouth shut.
好吧  是我的错
Fair enough.
给我说说单簧管  不对  是伯纳黛特的事吧
Now, what's up with Clarinet...? Bernadette!
我一直在想格林博士
I've been thinking about Dr. Greene's efforts
致力于把科学变得平民化的事
to make science palatable for the masses.
是吗  想出什么来了
Oh, yeah? What about it?
没什么  我就想了下
That's all. I've just been thinking about it.
现在  我在想分形方程
Now, I'm thinking about fractal equations.
现在我又在想
Now I'm thinking about
"思路"这词的词源
the origin of the phrase "train of thought."
现在我在想火车
Now I'm thinking about trains.
你在听他说话吗
Are you listening to this guy?
抱歉
Hmm? Oh, I'm sorry.
我在想别的
I was somewhere else.
你个幸运的混蛋
Lucky bastard.
现在我在想果冻
Now I'm thinking about Jell-O.
你怎么了
So what's up?
是关于伯纳黛特的事
It's a Bernadette thing.
不是吧  希望一切都好
Oh, no. I hope everything's okay.
不管怎样  我们都挺你的
Whatever it is, we're here for you.
你尽管畅所欲言
You can tell us anything.
对  不管是好事或悲剧
Yeah. Good or devastating.
我想求她嫁给我
I'm gonna ask her to marry me.
-嫁给你  -什么
- Marry you? - What?
我只想找个好时机求婚
I just need to figure out the right time to pop the question.
-还是等等吧  -别急  别急
- Oh, I'd wait.  - No rush, no rush.
太好了  是我表弟问我婚戒的事
Oh, great. It's my cousin David about the ring.
大卫  找得怎样
Hey, David, what'd you find?
没问题  半克拉就行
Sure, a half a caret's fine.
她那奇小的手  衬得啥都很大
Her freakishly small hands make anything look big.
这就是我爱她的其中一个理由
It's one of the reasons I love her.
天  他会大失所望的
Man, he's going to be blindsided.
我知道  绝对会很糟
I know. It'll be awful.
你为什么在笑
Why are you smiling?
对  拉杰  为什么
Yeah, Raj, why?
在我们印度  笑容有不一样含义
Uh, a smile means something different in my country.
比如高兴的泪水  悲哀的微笑
You know, tears of joy, smile of sadness.
印度是个傻地方
India's a goofy place.
哦  我又重新开始想火车了
Oh, I'm back to trains.
我有没告诉过你  我们实验室得到一笔拨款进行一项研究
Did I tell you our lab got a grant to study addiction?
-没有  -很赞的工作
- No. - Fascinating work.
我最近训练出一僧帽猴抽烟
I recently trained a capuchin monkey to smoke cigarettes.
研究到什么了吗
Have you learned anything?
有  它比不抽烟的猴子酷多了
Yes. He looks much cooler than the non-smoking monkeys.
当然这也不算项比赛
Although it's not much of a contest.
其他猴子光会闲坐着手淫
The other monkeys just sit around and masturbate.
你不介意的话
If you don't mind,
我想停止听你说话  开始发言
I'd like to stop listening to you and start talking.
当然
By all means.
霍华德刚宣布
Howard has announced his intention
他想向伯纳黛特求婚
to propose marriage to Bernadette.
我不明白
I don't understand.
八卦一开始不是说他们要分手吗
The original piece of gossip indicated an impending breakup.
就是说啊
I know.
我们一致认为他的求婚
The group consensus is that his proposal
将遭到让他丢脸心碎的拒绝
will be met with an humiliating, soul-crushing rejection.
大家的心情都紧张得要命
Everyone was set a-twitter.
虽然很奇怪  却没人发微薄
Although oddly, no one tweeted.
我并不奇怪这个故事
It's not surprising that the story
已得到我们小小朋友圈里人的注意
has captured the attention of our little circle of friends.
你了解模因理论吗
Are you familiar with Meme Theory?
我什么不了解啊  但继续
I'm familiar with everything, but go on.
模因理论认为
Meme Theory suggests that
八卦内容就像生物
items of gossip are like living things
力图利用人类作宿主迅速繁殖
that seek to reproduce using humans as their host.
我很清楚模因传染病学
I'm no stranger to memetic epidemiology.
在我就读的约翰逊小学
At Johnson Elementary School,
"谢耳朵是坨臭耳屎"这话就传播迅猛
the phrase "Shelly Cooper's a smelly pooper" spread like wildfire.
我想也是
I should think so.
这句话真是绝了
That's gold.
模因假设并不吸引我
Your meme hypothesis does intrigue me.
不如我们更近地检测下
How might we examine this more closely?
想用人类作实验  你一点都不觉得内疚吗
Do you have any ethical qualms regarding human experimentation?
这是极少几项跟人类相互交往
It's one of the few forms of interaction with people
不让我讨厌的
that I don't find repellent.
我们需要假造一则诱人的八卦
We need to fabricate a tantalizing piece of gossip.
再造一则不诱人的八卦作为实验的控制组
And a second non-tantalizing piece to use as a control.
然后追踪它在我们社交圈的发展情况
Then we'll track its progress through our social group
通过几项相互矛盾的理论来解释结果
and interpret the results through the competing academic prisms
如模因理论  代数八卦和传染病学
of memetic theory, algebraic gossip and epidemiology.
看看你  居然让我开始研究社会科学了
Look at you, getting me to engage in the social sciences.
你真坏  艾米·费拉·福勒
You're a vixen, Amy Farrah Fowler.
嘿  艾米  有事吗
Oh, hey, Amy. What's up?
我和谢尔顿上床了
Sheldon and I engaged in sexual intercourse.
还有  我想种个百草园
In other news, I'm thinking of starting an herb garden.
要保密哦  我走了
Mum's the word. Gotta go.
拉杰  你在这干嘛
Oh, hey, Raj, what are you doing here?
就想一个人喝喝酒
I just felt like drinking alone,
因为我深沉黑暗
because I'm deep and dark.
霍华德没来吗
So, uh, Howard's not here?
没  又是只有我和你了
No. It's just one of those times when it's just you and me.
就像上次我们仨去看电影
Like when the three of us went to the movies,
因为红蔓卷绳糖和樱桃可乐
and you and I waited outside the bathroom
霍华德躲在厕所里吐  咱俩就在外面等着
while Howard threw up Red Vines and Cherry Coke.
你还记得吗
Do you remember that?
记得
Yeah.
我也是
Me, too.
真是美好时光
Good times.
16桌要点头盘
16 wants to order appetizers.
-谢谢  -刚才的时光也很美好
- Oh, thanks. - This was nice.
你到底在这干嘛
What the hell are you doing?
霍华德是你最好的朋友  而那是他女友
Howard is your best friend, and that is his girlfriend.
你真该为自己感到羞耻
You should be ashamed of yourself.
我来的时候的确是
I was when I came in,
但美酒穿肠过  美人心中留
but it's amazing what liquor does to guilt.
还有你可能不知道
Besides what you might not know
伯纳黛特正准备跟霍华德分手呢
is Bernadette is planning on breaking up with Howard.
我知道  你又怎么知道的
Well, I know that. How do you know that?
我妹妹说的
My sister told me.
那个八卦的婊子
Oh, that gossipy bitch.
无意冒犯
No offense.
我不介意
None taken.
你真该听听她背后怎么说你的
You should hear how she talks about you.
好吧  听着
Okay, listen,
就算霍华德和贝纳黛特之间出了问题
just because Howard and Bernadette are having problems,
你也不应该在这四处打探
does not mean you should be here sniffing around.
我能怎么办  我脑子里想的都是她
What can I do? I can't stop thinking about her.
好吧  试着想想这个
All right, try thinking about this--
谢尔顿和艾米上床啦
Sheldon and Amy had sex.
闭上你的狗嘴
Shut your ass!
是真的  艾米亲口跟我说的
Yeah, it's true. Amy told me.
怎么可能发生这事呢
How did that even happen?
他们干的时候
Did they know that's what they were doing
知道自己在干嘛吗
when they were doing it?
我猜他们应该是灵机一动  于是激情喷涌
I-I guess they just figurd it out at some point.
真不敢相信老处男臭耳屎终于开苞了
I can't believe old Smelly Pooper finally got laid.
希望你饿了
Hope you're hungry.
有意思
Interesting.
这个国家表示友好的方式
A friendly sentiment in this country,
在苏丹却是残酷的奚落
cruel taunt in the Sudan.
不同语境的教训啊
It's a lesson in context.
艾米会来跟咱们一起吃饭吗
Will Amy be joining us for dinner?
应该会来吧
Yes, I believe so.
好  很好
Good, good.
你们俩  还好吧
Everything... okay between you two?
当然
Yes.
你问这个干嘛
Why do you ask?
没事随便问问
No reason.
我刚跟拉杰聊天
I was just talking to Raj,
他觉得艾米这几天容光焕发得不得了
and he mentioned what a lovely glow she has these days.
他是说那种容光是因为照料百草园时
Did he mean as if she'd been out in the sun,
没戴帽子或擦防晒  而被太阳晒成的吗
tending an herb garden without wearing a hat or sunblock?
不是
No.
他说的重点不是这个
That's not what he meant.
那我们就不得而知了
Well, we may never know.
正如我母亲常说
As my mother would say,
亚洲人高深莫测呀
the Asians are an inscrutable folk.
不好意思  我还有工作要忙
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have work to do.
你忙你忙
Yeah, you do.
小坏蛋  装毛呀装
You dog, you.
你听见了吗
Did you get that?
一字不差
Every word.
我们谣言八卦模因
Our false gossip meme
好像已经到达目录树中的节点表达式了
appears to have reached node lambda.
传递得比我们想象中要快
This is moving faster than we thought.
同意
Agreed.
似乎谣言的传播速率
It appears the rate of gossip transmission
与节点数量的二次幂成比例
is proportional to the number of nodes squared.
艾米  我不得不说
I must say, Amy,
假装跟你上床
pretending to have intercourse with you
让我的身心得到了极大的满足
is giving me a great deal of satisfaction.
慢点  谢尔顿  我还没啥感觉呢
Slow down, Sheldon. I'm not quite there yet.
-帮我递下酱油  -好的
- Pass the soy sauce. - sure
贝纳黛特刚向我打听咱俩上床的事
Bernadette just asked about my sexual encounter with you.
模因全面插入[penetration也有阴茎插入的意思]
The meme has reached full penetration.
故意用的双关语吗
Pun intended?
不是  无心插柳柳成荫
No. Happy accident.
这次成果显著
This is remarkable.
还不到24小时
Took less than 24 hours.
我应该告诉你
I should let you know
她还问了咱俩调情的细节
that she asked for details about our dalliance.
真有意思
Interesting.
人们开始不满足于"上床"的字面意思
So it went beyond the mere fact of coitus
发展到要咱俩"越吹越爽"的细节了
to a "blow by blow," as it were.
故意用的双关语吗
Pun intended?
抱歉  什么双关
I'm sorry. What pun?
不说这个了
Not important.
我把你的做爱方式概括为"冷淡却高效"
I described your lovemaking as "aloof, but effective."
但愿你没有说出口
I wish you hadn't done that.
这话说得我跟一个少妇杀手一样
That's going to make me a chick magnet,
而事实上  我非常忙
and I'm so busy as it is.
大家注意啦
Hey, everybody,
我有话要问贝纳黛特
I got something I want to ask Bernadette,
现在大伙儿齐聚一堂
and I can't think of a better time
天时地利人和都最佳的时候
than when I'm with all my friends.
慢着  霍华德
Oh, hold on, Howard.
还有更多天时更好的
There's lots of better times.
莱纳德  拜托  他说话呢
Leonard, please. The man is talking.
让他说出来  别管后果如何
Let him get it out, and let the chips fall where they may.
谢谢
Thank you.
贝纳黛特·玛丽安·罗森考斯基
Bernadette Maryann Rostenkowski...
天啊  这是什么回事
Oh, God. What's happening?
我知道我们的爱情不算完美
I know things haven't been perfect with us,
而且遇到了问题
and we've had our problems,
但我不得不告诉你  从我遇见你那刻
but I just have to tell you, from the moment I...
霍华德  你先别说
Howard, let me just stop you right here.
好戏上场
This is it.
我愿意
Yes.
你愿意什么
Yes, what?
我愿意嫁给你
Yes, I will marry you.
-你愿意?  - 你愿意?!
- You will? - You will?
我愿意!
I will.
I will!
我真的很爱你
Oh, I love you so much.
我也爱你
Oh, I love you, too.
恭喜你们
Congratulations!
这太激动人心了
Oh, it's so exciting.
我真纳闷她为什么改变主意
I wonder what changed her mind.
或许是因为你对我非凡性能力的谈论
Perhaps your talk of my sexual prowess
重燃了她对爱情的信心
renewed her faith in love.
没有比这更好的解释了
As good an explanation as any.
你戴着真漂亮
That's great...
嘿  艾米
Oh, hey, Amy.
伯纳黛特刚发短信给我
Bernadette just texted me.
霍华德求婚了
Howard proposed?
对  这个不重要  我只是路过
Yes, not important. Just stopped by
顺便告诉你一声  我准备做矫正术
to let you know I'm getting orthotics.
对了  我怀了谢尔顿的孩子
Also, I'm carrying Sheldon's baby.
要保密哦
Mum's the word.
你怀孕了
You're pregnant?!
哇哦  还有提到矫正术吗
Wow. Is there anything on there about orthotics?